Jackson Place Complex P021
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Jackson Place Complex Photograph Collection
1988
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
United States. General Services Administration
P021
1 Boxes
0.2 Linear feet
Arrangement
Processed at item level without series.
Biographical / Historical
The Jackson Place complex, known as the New Executive Office Building, is a ten story office building opened in 1969. The building is located at 725 17th Street, NW and shares a block with Blair House, Trowbridge House, Decatur House, and Renwick Gallery. The building was designed by John Carl Warnecke who sought to "harmonize [the structures] with Lafayette Square's historic character and retained the domestic facades but joined the separate interiors."
Custodial History
There is no deed of gift and it is uncertain as to how the Library acquired these photographs.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of 31 4x6 inch color and photocopied images of the Jackson Place complex. The photographs detail the buildings and its previous masonry and roofing repairs. There are three copies of each image making the total number of images 93. An envelope at the end of the packet contained the original negative for all of the images, except for the images that are photocopies. Additionally, there are 63 negatives without a corresponding print. The booklet was assembled for the General Services Administration, National Capital Region by the Einhorn Yaffe Prescott Architecture and Engineering, P.C. The booklet is entitled "Section 106 Compliance, Appendix D: Photographs."
Photographs; Buildings; Architecture
- Series 1
  - Architectural model of the Jackson Place Complex, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    (Photocopy, 3 copies)
  - General view of Jackson Place from Lafayette square, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    (3 copies)
  - General view of Jackson Place upper floors and roofs from Lafayette square, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General view of Jackson Place from Lafayette square, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General view of the rear of Jackson Place, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General view of plaza behind Jackson Place, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rear steps of building #734, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Detail and planter box behind #722, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Typical interior wall damage caused by leaking gutters, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - East half of #708 parapet wall, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Detail of paint on parapet wall, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Walking parapet of #708 from roof of #712, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Failed parging at truncated chimney of #712, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Metal barrel dormers at #712, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Detail of typical patching and repair of #712, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - South face of parapet between #708 and #712, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - South face of #716 chimney, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - East facing dormers of #718, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Detail of gutter intersection between #716 and #718, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - West-facing mansard roof of #726-A, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Typical sealant joint failure of cast stone, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - East facing dormer cladding at #736, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Built in gutter and gravel-stop details at #734 and #736, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Early surface-rusting at #740, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Roof of #744 looking northeast, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - South end of Jackson Place, ca. 1920 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    (photocopy, 3 copies)
  - Blair-Lee Houses and Renwick Gallery, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - North face of building #736, ca. 1902 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Building #734 and #736, ca. 1920 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Building #722, ca. 1930 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Jackson Place looking southwest, ca. 1934 (Box 1, Folder 31)